<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Zen Savona</title>
 <link href="http://zensavona.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://zensavona.com"/>
 <updated>2012-09-03T11:12:18+10:00</updated>
 <id>http://zensavona.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Zen Savona</name>
   <email>z@zensavona.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Get your shit together, people</title>
   <link href="http://zensavona.com/2012/get-your-shit-together-people"/>
   <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zensavona.com/2012/get-your-shit-together-people</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I live in Brisbane, Australia. My only real window to what is happening in silicon valley is HN and the blogs of various founders and VCs from the valley. If my assumptions are completely wrong, please do let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id='shitty_products'&gt;Shitty products&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now in the world there are so many talented and skilled developers - why are so many of us working on such shitty, menial ideas? I mean there are exceptions - but it also seems like there are &lt;i&gt;so many&lt;/i&gt; people working on &lt;i&gt;really stupid things&lt;/i&gt;. No, I &lt;i&gt;don't&lt;/i&gt; want to sign up to your bootstrap themed product which looks like it was thrown together in a week and performs no valuable purpose to my daily life (which I can&amp;#8217;t replicate more elegantly with a text file). It seems like we are becoming so intent on &amp;#8216;shipping&amp;#8217; &lt;i&gt;something&lt;/i&gt;, that we are willing to throw &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; out there and hope that by chance, we make something that &lt;i&gt;someone, somewhere&lt;/i&gt; wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mariusandra.com/blog/2012/08/stop-producing-shit/'&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href='http://mariusandra.com/'&gt;Marius Andra&lt;/a&gt; really struck a chord with me and somewhat inspired this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine is starting what can only be described as a combination of Facebook, Groupon, LinkedIn and Foursquare. He’s super excited and hasn’t talked to any potential customers yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know a guy whose startup pivots twice a year, each time hoping to solve a problem that’s not really there. Now they’re cloning Yammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other guys had an idea, received validation from two potential clients, raised funding, hired a lot of people, built a product and discovered nobody really wants to pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a thought, spend more time on something which you know is great, and launch it with polish. Don&amp;#8217;t ship your &lt;i&gt;shitty, half baked product&lt;/i&gt; - launch it well and give people something to gasp at. Until then, keep thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='the_startup_romantic_era'&gt;The startup &amp;#8220;romantic era&amp;#8221;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are treating business like it&amp;#8217;s a fucking &lt;i&gt;art form&lt;/i&gt;. If you haven&amp;#8217;t already seen this, read a couple of posts on &lt;a href='http://doublestealth.blogspot.com'&gt;Double Stealth&lt;/a&gt;, if this sounds anything like you, go find a mirror, look into it for a long time and seriously thing about what you doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember this: business is about selling things to people. People are just like you - if you are working on something which you would not personally &lt;strong&gt;stand outside in the cold for a couple of hours to pay money for&lt;/strong&gt;, you&amp;#8217;re probably doing it wrong (Well, not quite to that extent, but I&amp;#8217;m sure you know what I mean).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='People waiting to buy some cool-ass shiny Apple shit' src='http://www-bgr-com.vimg.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/beijingchina-iphone-4s-launch.jpeg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing to remember is that most consumers &lt;i&gt;do not really care&lt;/i&gt; about (or understand) how your product is &lt;i&gt;slightly better&lt;/i&gt; in some way than what they use right now - for them, it&amp;#8217;s much easier to stick with writing shit down on a piece of paper than figure out how to use your swanky web-based AJAXy responsive &amp;#8216;disruptive&amp;#8217; to-do list which syncs between multiple devices and uses local storage for fast access to data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give them something they are &lt;strong&gt;genuinely amazed by&lt;/strong&gt; - I remember when I first saw an iPhone 3G in the flesh (the original iPhone was never released in Australia). My friend came over to my place one afternoon and showed me this new phone of his (at the time I had one of &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTC_TyTN_II'&gt;these babies&lt;/a&gt;, a HTC TyTN II) I had never used a capacitive touchscreen before and thought it was &lt;strong&gt;fucking magical&lt;/strong&gt;. Needless to say, I went and bought one as soon as my high-school job allowed me to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story is that you need to make products which make people do &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt;. Build something so awesome that it sells itself, I had never seen an Apple commercial or read the tech-specs - but after playing with it in my hands for a couple of minutes I was absolutely sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more examples of products like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://github.com/'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://heroku.com/'&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://gmail.com/'&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://spotify.com/'&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://dropbox.com/'&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='now_stop_sipping_soy_lattes_in_a_cafe_behind_your_macbook_reading_hacker_news_and_pondering_which_company_you_want_your_shitty_little_insignificant_thing_to_be_acquired_by_and_build_something_'&gt;Now stop sipping soy lattes in a cafe behind your Macbook, reading Hacker News and pondering which company you want your shitty little insignificant thing to be acquired by, and build something &lt;i&gt;which makes people's fucking jaw drop&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What App.net really can be (if we let it)</title>
   <link href="http://zensavona.com/2012/what-appnet-really-can-be-if-we-let-it"/>
   <updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zensavona.com/2012/what-appnet-really-can-be-if-we-let-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You need to stop thinking that &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; is a Twitter clone right now, because it&amp;#8217;s not. Think of the &amp;#8216;alpha&amp;#8217; in alpha.app.net as indicating not only that what we see is an alpha version of their web app (which is powered by the much tech blog ignored API) but an alpha model and example of one of numerous ways to consume the API&amp;#8217;s data. What needs to happen is that &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s API becomes a high quality, developer friendly, secure &amp;#8216;social network in a box&amp;#8217;, which developers can use to build applications whom all have &amp;#8216;first class citizen&amp;#8217; access to the user&amp;#8217;s information, posts, messages, relationships, privacy settings etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='users_as_a_service'&gt;Users as a service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developer accounts (or, API access) need to be &amp;#8216;users as a service&amp;#8217;, rather than &amp;#8216;just an API&amp;#8217;. I think the reason people aren&amp;#8217;t going as crazy as they could be over this is that they don&amp;#8217;t realise what it actually is. Tech blogs have been promoting App.net as an alternative to Twitter (which it is, but that&amp;#8217;s only one small part), when it has the potential to become membership to a &amp;#8216;club&amp;#8217; of high quality web communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='why_appnet_will_succeed_or_at_least_why_i_think_it_will'&gt;Why App.net will succeed (or at least why I think it will)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been said by many people (and notably &lt;a href='http://samsoff.es/posts/app-net-is-dreaming-small'&gt;Sam&lt;/a&gt;) that App.net is not throwing a wide enough net. I disagree, I think the choice of targeting developers first is a good one - developers are early adopters by nature, and by (initially) making this a community of primarily tech people they are enlisting the best possible group to give quality feedback about the API. A great API will lead to great things being built on top of it, which will potentially lead to more widespread adoption. Dalton and his team are niching to win and my opinion is that they are doing it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='introducing_friendleme'&gt;Introducing &lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me'&gt;Friendle.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I upgraded from my backer account to a developer account on &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few things I&amp;#8217;ve been itching to build, but one particular idea really stood out: &lt;strong&gt;Friendle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friendle will be a high quality social community, powered by the App.net API. It will be a way of keeping up with people you know and connect with on &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; powered services, you could think of it as a service which draws some ideas from &lt;a href='http://facebook.com'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://plus.google.com'&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://alpha.app.net'&gt;alpha.app.net&lt;/a&gt;. For a much more detailed explanation, you can read &lt;a href='http://zensavona.com/2012/introducing-friendle/'&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Right now I have just put a splash page up, but you can &lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me/'&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; with your &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; account and be notified when an alpha version of Friendle is availble.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing Friendle</title>
   <link href="http://zensavona.com/2012/introducing-friendle"/>
   <updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zensavona.com/2012/introducing-friendle</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using &lt;a href='https://alpha.app.net'&gt;alpha.app.net&lt;/a&gt; for the past few days and it has given me so many ideas as to how a social community should function. Particularly the way conversations and user relationships should be handled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='both_facebook_and_twitters_approach_to_handling_user_relationships_are_broken'&gt;Both Facebook and Twitters approach to handling user relationships are broken&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook&amp;#8217;s friend system does not scale well (hence the need for like pages, which in turn have their own set of problems), Twitter&amp;#8217;s follower system is better, but still not perfect. I think there can be a better solution, which is why I am building Friendle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friendle will be a high quality social community, powered by the App.net API. It will be a way of keeping up with people you know and connect with on &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; powered services, you could think of it as a service which draws some ideas from &lt;a href='http://facebook.com'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://plus.google.com'&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://alpha.app.net'&gt;alpha.app.net&lt;/a&gt;. For a much more detailed explanation, you can read &lt;span&gt;this blog post&lt;/span&gt;. Right now I have just put a splash page up, but you can &lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me/'&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; with your &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; account and be notified when an alpha version of Friendle is availble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='register_your_interest_now'&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me/'&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; now!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why working is a scam</title>
   <link href="http://zensavona.com/2012/why-working-is-a-scam"/>
   <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zensavona.com/2012/why-working-is-a-scam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id='working_a_real_job_is_a_scam'&gt;Working a &amp;#8220;real&amp;#8221; job is a scam.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Australia, the average life expectency is 81. Let&amp;#8217;s assume for a moment that a person starts working full time at 21 and retires at 60, this is assuming you are earning an above average salary (the &amp;#8220;retirement age&amp;#8221; in Australia is actually 65). This means you will work full time for 39 years. If you average 4 full work days per week over your working life, you will have spent just &lt;strong&gt;over 22 years&lt;/strong&gt; at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='why_do_we_do_this'&gt;Why do we do this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you are an exception and absolutely love your 9-5 job, you are effectively wasting &lt;strong&gt;over a quarter of your life&lt;/strong&gt; doing something purely to survive. When it&amp;#8217;s put that way, that $100k you earn (if you&amp;#8217;re lucky) sounds pretty unattractive, doesn&amp;#8217;t it? I mean, if you&amp;#8217;re working for your self there is the potential to earn so much more - and that&amp;#8217;s not even the best part&amp;#8230; &lt;strong&gt;Working for yourself frees you from so many restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;. Want to take that 7 day trip to Melbourne? Go for it, just take your laptop along and put in a couple of hours a night in your hotel room. Want to backpack across South East Asia? Go for it!. You can be living any kind of life you want, while your friends are stuck in the office watching the clock and planning their weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='its_not_for_everyone'&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not for everyone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are happy with your corporate job, good for you. The point of this post is not to tell everyone what they should do, but to point out that if you are not happy doing what you&amp;#8217;re currently doing, &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;#8217;t just suck it up, do something else&lt;/strong&gt; because right now, especially in IT, if your business idea fucks up, there are plenty of other jobs. The days of working with one company and scaling up the corporate ladder until you reach your comfortable seat on a high branch are over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just be prepared for a long and often uncertain journey. The good stuff doesn&amp;#8217;t come easy. &lt;i&gt;(Tim Westergren, Pandora)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now stop being lazy and go take some risks, &lt;strong&gt;because if you fail, at least you can say you tried&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why you should never use GoDaddy again</title>
   <link href="http://zensavona.com/2012/why-you-should-never-use-godaddy-ever-again"/>
   <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zensavona.com/2012/why-you-should-never-use-godaddy-ever-again</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although this is untimately my fault, because I had the thought in the back of my mind at the time, I happened to be on GoDaddy&amp;#8217;s site for something work related and had the &amp;#8220;it won&amp;#8217;t happen to me&amp;#8221; mentality at the time, so I quickly checked if an idea for a domain for my side-project was available because it popped to mind in that moment. It was&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;cool&amp;#8221; I thought, and continued with my work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 3 days later, I remembered that domain and went into my webhost&amp;#8217;s (not GoDaddy) control panel to register said domain and run into this&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error: xxxxxxxxx.com is already registered and is not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, really you assholes? A quick whois search and I find this&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registered through: GoDaddy.com, LLC (http://www.godaddy.com)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I search again for the domain on GoDaddy, they prompt me to buy it with their &amp;#8220;Domain buying service&amp;#8221;, and pay the charges associated. I am not buying the domain out of principle. Go die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose there is nothing &amp;#8216;wrong&amp;#8217; with this business practice, of analysing the user&amp;#8217;s interest in the domain and buying it if their algorithm thinks that you want it. But I certainly will never use their services again after this. Back to &lt;a href='http://domai.nr/'&gt;domai.nr&lt;/a&gt; for my domain hunting quests.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>